参见玉帝⋯
Greetings to your highness
众卿家大发雷霆　所为何事
Ministers, why are you so mad?
王母　你先讲
Queen Mother, you first
玉帝啊　降龙罗汉
Your highness, Dragon Fighter Lo Han stole all the peaches…
把我那棵蟠桃树上的蟠桃
全都偷去给牛郎的牛吃了
…from my peach tree for the Cowherd's cows
还不止呢
Not only that, he also conspired with Magpie to arrange…
他还串通那些喜鹊天天架起鹊桥
…the Cowherd & Spinster Maid rendezvous on the bridge
让牛郎织女幽会　丑大了
已经生下一打孩子了
Damn it! They've bred lots of children now
哇
玉帝啊　向来凡间男女关系
Your highness, all along I've handled…
一向由我来掌管
…lovers' relationships in the mortal world
谁知他来到这里乱搞一通
Who would have thought he'd mess it up,
搞得皇帝要去追〝野鸡〞
such that the emperor woos a whore,
堂堂一个公主要跟乞丐私奔呢
and a princess elopes with a beggar
我才说了他两句
I reprimanded him gently,
他就偷了我的哮天犬　煮了吃了
he then stole my Heavenly Dog and braised it with bamboo shoots
嗯　你又是什么人呢
Now who might you be?
在下二郎神
I'm God No. 2
玉帝　我这只眼
Your highness, my eye was also blinded by that bastard
也是被那王八蛋给弄瞎的
这一只呢也是哮天犬的替身
This is just a substitute for Heavenly Dog
国有国法　天有天条
Law and order must be enforced
这个降龙目无王法
This Dragon Fighter is outrageous
我希望玉帝批准我揍他
I hope your highness permits me to beat him up
哼　财神　你也不必这么冲动啊
God of Fortune, stay calm
哼　这些都是小事
These are small matters.
他偷了我的生死簿　改得一塌糊涂
He stole my Book of Destiny and messed it up
凡间已经十八年没死过人了
There hasn't been a death in 18 years
弄得那些仵作都没事做
Those undertakers are out of work,
还出了个五六百岁的人魔
and there's a centuries-old man
玉帝　你不摆平这个混蛋
Your highness, if you can't control him,
我阎王一定告到九重天　小事化大
I'll bring this up with the Ninth Heaven
and make a great fuss
来人呢　替我抓降龙上殿
Guards, summon Dragon Fighter to the palace
是
Yes
哎⋯哎哟⋯不要这么用劲儿嘛
Hey… not so hard
我正在睡午觉
I'm taking a nap, brother
怎么　大家都来了　各位
Hey… everybody is here
What?
你又不是降龙　你是伏虎　你来干吗
You're not Dragon Fighter, you're Tiger Fighter
都一样嘛　降龙伏虎都一样嘛
It's just the same Dragon and Tiger are the same
伏虎
Tiger Fighter
哎　是　玉帝
Yes, your highness
没你的事　你干吗上来呀
It doesn't concern you. Why are you here?
哎　我是代表降龙来跟大家道歉的
I represent Dragon Fighter to apologize to you all
你这么讲义气　难道你也有份
You speak so loyally,
are you also a part of this?
哎⋯不关我的事啊
Hey! What has it to do with me? I…
哎　神仙就大了
Do you think fairies can get away with everything?
Ai! Aiya…
伏虎　你真是个管家婆
Tiger Fighter, you really are interfering,
不过你还挺讲义气　我心领了
yet you're a loyal friend.
I appreciate it
哎　谢谢⋯
Thanks…
哎　照目前情形看起来
Hey, as things stand,
随便认个错马上走算了
just make an apology and leave
随便认错就想走
Do you think you can leave just by saying sorry?
我们俩兄弟聊天　几时轮到你插嘴
Who are you to interrupt our conversation?
嘿呀　你这个灶君
God of Hearth, each year-end… …you seek advantage in the mortal world,
每逢年尾就想在下面搞便宜
人家不给你
and speak ill of those families who gave you less
你就到上面来说人家不是　插他
- Poke him    - Poke him
插他
啊　刚才插完好痛　现在又要插
Hey! You just did and it still hurts, don't poke again
You, a petty Lo Han,
小小一个罗汉　什么事情你都要管
poke your nose in everybody's business
岂有此理　你偷吃我的蟠桃　赔来
Outrageous! You better compensate me
for the stolen peaches
王母　吃一点人家也没说什么
Queen Mother, what's the big deal to share some to others?
什么
What?
那蟠桃也该吃腻了吧
You must get fed up with peaches on your birthday each year
什么
What?
今年换换口味吃香蕉好了
Why not have a change and eat bananas this year
啊
What?
干吗　不服气就冲我来
Tell me frankly if you're still angry
不要叫你的狗在那边乱吠
Don't have your dog howl for you
别以为换了一只斑点我就不敢吃
Don't think just because he has spots
我照吃不误　到哪一个了
I can sock all the same, I'm telling you
Who's next?
到哪一个了　就你好了
You will do
You Moon Match-maker,
你这个月老　仗着几根破烂红绳
you fool humans with several red strings
没事就胡牵乱扯
就好像梁山伯与祝英台
Take for instance the Butterfly Lovers,
为什么不肯把他们拴在一起
why not tie them together?
搞得他们扑坟吐血
Instead you brought them a tragic ending,
他们哪里对不起你了
what have they done to you to deserve this?
我说你老了　没事就退休吧
You're old, you should retire…
…before you make a mess Who knows, you may make wacky matches…
不然将来牵错了红绳
弄得男跟男　女跟女
…say like a man with a man, a woman with a woman,
再弄下去　人跟猪　蟑螂配牛了
or even a man with a pig, a roach with a cow
最惨的是蚂蚁跟大象啊
- Worst of all would be a lotus root with a rock    - Yes
哎　插他
Poke him
哎　人家年纪不小了　不要欺负他
He's old, spare him
哎呀　你想管闲事吗　阎罗王
King of Hades, are you standing up for him?
插他了
Poke him
不要碰面就插　我们是讲道理的
Don't keep saying poke, we should be reasonable
Your hand…
为什么凡间有个女子
Why there's a woman in the mortal world who bore 16 daughters…
连生了十六个女儿
就不肯给她一个儿子　为什么
…and was denied a boy? Why?
搞得那个女的终于想不开　跳海自尽
Consequently she jumped into the sea to kill herself
啊
到了下面　他还说她是枉死的
Even in hell, he accused her of innocent death,
把她丢到油锅里炸得跟麻花似的
flung her into a frying pan
and fried her to a crisp
你说天理何在呀
Do you think there's justice?
降龙⋯
Lung… Dragon Fighter…
昏过去也没有用啊
Fainting is no use.
凡人的命运早已经成定数　并无不妥
People's fate is predestined
There's nothing wrong about it
由不得你在这儿无理取闹
So you shouldn't make trouble here
我只是照例执行
- We're only carrying out orders    - Your highness…
哎　我⋯
Carrying out orders?
谁说照例执行　谁订的令
Who set them?
谁说一定是对的
Who dares to say it must be right?
常言道天外有天
A saying goes, ‘There are other heavens’
玉帝　你定的例
Your highness, if your rules…
要是让九重天的菩萨给听见
were known by Bodhisattva in the Ninth Heaven,
只怕会是白痴说笑话
she'll think this is a joke of a moron
太过分了
This is out of line
玉帝　各位仙友
Your highness, fairies,
本人觉得降龙罗汉实在太嚣张了
reckon Dragon Fighter Lo Han is just too rampant
我财神为了顾全大局
I think, for everybody's advantage,
请玉帝批准我跟他单挑
please allow me to fight him one on one
笑死人了　你打得过他吗
- Haha…    - Shut up! You better shut up
我要跟他单挑
哎　算了⋯
- I want to fight him one on one    - Don't kill him
我要跟他拼了　我不会放过他的
I'll not show him mercy
I won't let you go
哎⋯吓死我⋯
Scare me
听着　就算天条有什么不对
Listen! Even if there's a loophole in the laws of Heaven,
总有一条可以定你们的罪
there must be one that convicts you
押他们到凡间去
Escort them to the mortal world
一个做猪　一个做狗
and make them a pig and a dog
十世不得轮回
No transmigration for them in 10 lifetimes
且慢
Wait
什么事
What is it?
你说做就做啊
Is your word final?
我说就算
Sure
我说你做蟑螂　你怎么说
I say you'll be a roach, let's go together
押啊⋯押他们下去
Escort them down
What?
啊　哎　慢点　观音来了
Wait! Don't…
参见大士⋯
Greetings to Goddess
玉帝　我们每一位成仙至今
Heavenly Highness, each one of us has been a fairy…
少说也有个万二八千年了
…for at least ten of thousands of years
世情种种　凡间一切在我们来说
Worldly affairs to us…
是遥远而微不足道
今日被降龙罗汉这么一闹
…are distant and trivial
或者是一个机缘
The mess Dragon Fighter Lo Han has caused today
为什么不借这个机缘
might be an opportunity
来了解一下凡人
是不是仍然那么愚昧无知
Why not use it to understand the mortal world?
抑或有所进步呢
To see if humans are still dumb and ignorant,
or they have progressed?
啊　听观音大士说话真是好听啊
Goddess of Mercy speaks well
哎　舒服　舒服
What a relief…
大士
Goddess,
这小子以替人家打抱不平为借口
this kid offends a superior…
以下犯上
…under the pretext of fighting injustice
你不要乱说话　阎罗王
Stop speaking nonsense, King of Hades
慢点　大士自有分寸
Matters will be taken care of by the Goddess
降龙　你做了这么多的事情
Dragon Fighter, what's your purpose of doing this?
目的何在
我只是想让这一班高高在上的神仙
I want these fairies to get off their high horses,
能够好好地真正地体验一下凡人
and experience the mortal world
因为这些凡人只有几十年的命
Humans only live for a few decades,
不要因为做错了一两件事就翻不了身
and they shouldn't be condemned for a mistake or two
因为小弟我相信
Because, according to my opinion,
无论他们是多么的笨　多么的无知
regardless of how ignorant and dumb they are,
怎么凶　怎么该死也好
how evil and deserving of death,
始终都是⋯
they are after all… after all…
是这个⋯
讲啊⋯快说呀⋯
After what…
Go on
哎　是这个⋯
I mean… after all…
都是人间有情
Subject to sympathy and love
是不是　降龙
Right, Dragon Fighter?
是啊　就是这样
Yes, that's it
哎　我看就由你开始
亲自下凡间去体验一下
Let's begin with you, going down to the mortal world
你有没有这个胆量啊
to experience it. Alright?
哟　我怕你啊　我正有此意
In fact that's what I intend to do
那你拿什么证明呢
How are you going to prove it?
我已经选了三个人
We've chosen 3 people
这三个人的命运已经注定了
with predestined fates
一个做九世乞丐
One will be a beggar for 9 lives
一个做九世〝野鸡〞
One a prostitute for 9 lives,
一个做九世恶人
and one a villain for 9 lives
Dragon Fighter,
如果你能够改变这三个人命运的话
if you can change their fates,
就算你赢
then you win
你说我们神仙都这么坏
Since you despise gods, alright,
好　你就用凡人的身份下去
you'll go as a layman…
不准用法力
…and not allowed to use magic
啊⋯不用法力⋯
No magic?
不用法力也是对的
That's right, Dragon Fighter
降龙　就用你的诚意去感化他们
Use your sincerity to reform them
好　我保证不会让你失望
Okay, I'll not fail you
你等我
Wait for me
我就给你三天的时间
I'll give you 3 days
谢谢　不过两天半就够了
Thanks
But two and a half days will do
(Southern Heaven Gate)
你不一定要听
但是今天我所说的一切
You don't have to listen
将来如果你不照着做
but if you don't act accordingly,
就不要妄想重返天庭
don't expect to return to Heaven
第一　除非你有公文批准
Firstly, unless you have the official permit,
否则不能擅自进入天庭
you can't enter Heaven
第二　你不可以带任何的法力下去
Secondly, you can't take magic powers with you
阿龙⋯一路顺风
Ah Lung… Lung
Bon voyage
彼此　彼此
Same to you
好兄弟啊
Good brothers
好兄弟　还有什么话跟我说
What else do you have for me?
你死定了　你打也不会打
You're dead
You can't fight and can't use magic
法力也不准用　你到下面去死定了
You're bound to die in the mortal world
谢谢
Thanks
不用客气
- Don't mention it    - Dragon Fighter,
降龙　你不会死的
you won't die
你在凡间轮回的时候
When you re-incarnate in the mortal world,
留下了一个金身
a golden body has been left behind
只要找到金身合而为一
Once you find and combine with it,
就可以保住肉身不灭
you can preserve your physical body,
可以穿梭阴阳间
and transmigrate between the mortal and spiritual worlds
也要靠它才能够返回天庭
Besides, with it you can return to Heaven too
实在太好了
Splendid
这次的旅程险阻重重
This journey will be filled with danger
送你一把心想事成扇
I'll present you with a Fan of Wishes…
这把扇每天只能够用三次
…which can only be used 3 times daily
每用一次就会出现裂痕一道
A crack will arise after each use
三次之后就要等第二天日出
After 3 times, you'll have to wait till the next day
裂痕自动消失方可再用
when the cracks vanish
嗯　一天三次　太可怜了
A mere 3 times a day, that's pathetic
哎　总比没有好啊
It's better than nothing
这把扇不能改变生死
This fan can't change life and death
不能改变人心意愿
nor manipulate free will
只不过是一些障眼法
It's just a sleight of hand,
不过凡人往往会迷惑于眼前的事物
but laymen are often bewitched by what they see
所以足够你应付的
So it would serve you well
谢谢大士
Thank you, Goddess
凡事小心　切记千万不要堕入邪道
Be careful and don't go astray
我知道了啦
I understand
大士摆明是帮你啊
Hey… Goddess does care much about you
没有这把扇子你就糟透了
You'd be in deep shit without this fan
是啊⋯
- Yes…    - Go down
哎⋯降龙
Hey… Dragon Fighter
哎　你是不是存心整他　他扇子都没有拿
Hey, you kick him down on purpose
你就这样把他踢下去了
He hasn't got the fan yet
玉帝规定是这个时辰
Heavenly Highness has set the deadline
什么玉帝规定啊
Hey, what's Heavenly Highness has ordered?
哎　我问你　你是干什么吃的你　啊
Hey, have you no sense of responsibility?
哎　你在这儿干什么
Hey, what are you doing here?
换班
Change of shift
哎　那好啊　跟我一道把扇子送给降龙
Good! Let's go down and pass the fan to Dragon Fighter
哎　你没有谕令
Hey… you don't have approval, and you have no magical powers in the mortal world
到了下面你又没有法力
凡人根本看不见你啊
Laymen can't see you
所以才让你跟我一块儿下去
That's why I want you to join me
这里除了玉帝之外
Besides Heavenly Highness,
只有你一个人可以随便出入的　哎　走
only you can come and go as you please
哎　不行　犯天条的
No, this is against heavenly rules
哎呀　犯什么天条嘛　去一次嘛
Forget about the rules.
Just fly once We'll be back soon. Let's go.
很快就回来的　走啊
我不去
I'm not going
降龙煮哮天神犬那天你也吃了
You've eaten the Heavenly Dog cooked by Dragon Fighter that day
王母娘娘的蟠桃你吃了两只
You've had 2 bites of the Queen Mother's peaches too
九天玄女两个婢女洗澡那天
That day while the Ninth Heaven Fairy's maids were taking a bath,
你这个王八蛋　翘起来了
you bastard…
…peeped
别嚷嚷　别嚷嚷嘛
Hey… Stop it! Don't expose it
你是不是犯贱呢
Creep!
一定要把你的丑事翻出来你才肯就范
You won't yield without threats
早去早回
Come back early
怕了嘛
You are sacred, aren't you?
我怕你　我怕你可以了吧
It's not good to let others know
(Guo Ching Temple)
左右两边是十八罗汉
The eighteen Lo Hans are on both sides
降龙伏虎在这一边
Dragon and Tiger Fighters are on this side
至于求子嘛⋯就要拜观音大士
To ask for a son,
you need to pray to Goddess of Mercy
大慈大悲观世音菩萨
Goddess of Mercy,
求你保佑我生下麟儿
do bless me with a son
希望大士真的显灵　要不然的话⋯
Hope Goddess'll show her power, otherwise…
过了今年我可就四十岁了
…I'll be forty next year
我李茂春任节度使多年
I, Li Mau Cheun, have been honest
自认为官清廉　问心无愧
as an envoy all these years
子嗣不需要太强求
With a clear conscience, we don't need to make demands for it
老说什么你一清如水　凡事不强求
Yes, just because you are honest,
那上天为什么要我们李家绝后呢
Heaven will not destine us to be without descendants
大师
Master
哎　左右两边是十八罗汉
The eighteen Lo Hans are on both sides
降龙伏虎在这边　如果求子⋯
Dragon and Tiger Fighters on this side
To ask for a son…
大师　你刚才已经说过了
- Master, you said just now    - Goodbye…
啊　再见⋯
我们还没拜神呢
We haven't prayed to the gods yet
哦　拜神⋯
Pray…
降龙罗汉
Dragon Fighter Lo Han?
哎　大师　我们想⋯
Master, we want…
哦　我记得　要儿子嘛
I remember. You want a son, right?
没问题
No problem
该不会又怀了十八个月还生不下来吧
Hasn't been a delivery even after 18 months’ pregnancy
夫人　用不着这么担心
Don't worry, madam
老爷、夫人　你们看
Master, madam, look
在哪儿摘的
- Where did you pluck it?    - Over there
就在那边摘的
老爷　怎么会这样呢　老爷　夫人
- Master, why?    - Master, madam
以前显贵诞生就会有灵芝异象出现
Whenever a noble is born,
Ling Tze plant will appear
但是现在这么看起来的话
From the way things look,
我们这位未出世的少爷一定是贵人呢
our future young master
must be a dignitary
现在弄得满屋都是冬菇
The house is now full of mushrooms
夫人　这孩子⋯
Madam, this child…
你自己跟他说吧　他就快要出来了
Tell him yourself, he's coming out
恭喜老爷　夫人生了
Congratulations, master! Madam has given birth
男的还是女的
A son or a daughter?
是少爷　恭喜老爷⋯
- A son! Congratulations, master    - Congratulations, master…
哎　怎么会掉到这里来呀
Hey… why have we landed here?
这是什么地方啊
What's this place?
大街
The main street
大街　去你妈的大街
Main street? Damn you
我叫你带我去降龙投胎那个地方
I asked you to take me to Dragon Fighter's birthplace
多走几条街就到了嘛
Just a few streets further
这样也会降落错
How could you land in the wrong place
谁让你刚晃来晃去的
Who asked you to rock so much
儿子究竟上哪儿去了
Where's our son?
I don't know either
我也不知道啊
Aiya… damn… it's really painful… really…
天杀的　他妈的　那家馆子吃完了之后
Damn, everyone got diarrhea
每一个人都拉肚子
after eating at that restaurant
就是⋯
- Damn it    - Damn it
麻烦一下　茅房借用一下　十万火急
Could we please use your manure pit?
- It's urgent    - Yes…
我们只有两间茅房　请便吧
We only have two
Help yourself
I can't hold on
他们俩跑得还真快啊
- So graceless    - They run so swiftly
我快憋不住了
I can hardly hold on
So this is the right place?
哎　降龙⋯
Dragon Fighter
哇　老兄　我等你好久了
Brother, I waited for ages, brother
哎　不关我的事
Not my fault!
哎　是麒麟怪带着我东跑西跑的
This bastard misled me
哎　别说那么多了　快点拿回你的扇子
Never mind, take your fan, here…
哇　我叫你买两只蟋蟀
- Quick and give them to me    - Hey… Lung…
你怎么去这么久啊
What took you ages to buy 2 crickets?
哎　我是精挑细选选两只
- I hand-picked two that fight best    - Brag
哎　阿龙　糟糕　他根本看不见我
Lung… Oh God! He can't see me
他已经是个凡人了　你想跟他接触
He is a layman now.
To contact him,
就要投胎转世变成肉身
you must re-incarnate and become human
他已经长这么大了　投胎也来不及了
He's now grown; too late for re-incarnation I guess
上面一天　凡间就十年
A day in Heaven is ten years in the mortal world
但是别怕　我会把你吹大的
Don't worry! I'll blow you up
嗯　吹大
Blow me up?
不过你会失去法力哦
But you'll lose your magic powers
after blowing up,
就算变成了凡人　也会是个白痴
and you'll become a moron when back to Heaven
哎　变成白痴跟他接触也没用了
Then it'll be no use contacting him
if I become a moron
你不明白的　当乌云盖月的时候
When the moon is clouded,
上面的监视是最弱的
the surveillance in Heaven is the weakest, understand?
到时候你再静悄悄地取回法力啊
You could secretly steal back your magical powers then
干吗声音这么小啊
Why such a soft voice?
这里没有人听到我们说话
Nobody will hear us
Big tummy. This one will do
哎　大肚子　哎　就这个好了
I'll take this one
动作快一点
Be nimble
我上这一个
我来投胎喽
I'm going to re-incarnate
哎　好舒服　该你了⋯
So comfortable. Your turn
哦　来了
Coming
哎⋯不要走开呀　哎哟　老太婆也认了
Hey… don't go away
Don't let go even a granny
啊　这怎么回事啊
Make my tummy so big
哎　真舒服
It's tough! Hey… your tummy?
啊⋯你的肚子⋯
哎呀　糟糕　扇子忘了　快⋯
Shit! I've forgotten the fan
Fix it
啊⋯哎⋯生了⋯
Coming…
哎呀　原来要生孩子
So she's giving birth
我们快点去准备一下　帮帮他们嘛
Let's get prepared and help them
啊⋯哎⋯老婆　是男的还是女的
Darling, a son or a daughter?
生把扇子
- It's a fan    - What?
Ah
我生了　生了个儿子
- What?    - Delivered… I've delivered
生下来了是吧　好⋯
You've delivered… Come…
来⋯快点把这个肚兜给围上啊
Put this belly-band on. My son Sau Yun…
这个肚兜啊　是我修缘小时候穿过的
…wore it when he was a child
怎么会这样　我也不知道
It would just fit him now
现在给他穿上就刚刚好了
来⋯我来把你吹大
Blow you up now
What?
再吹一下
- One more time    - What
What?
搞定了
Done
妖怪呀⋯
Demon, run quickly…
哎　这个人会不会是妖怪呀
Is this some demon or what?
妖什么怪　他会变戏法
Nonsense! He's just playing magic tricks
你会不会变戏法
Do you know how to perform magic?
老爷　我去报官
Master, how about reporting it to the magistracy?
报什么官　我不就是官吗
What for? I'm a magistrate
哎呀　还是把他留下来好了
Let him stay. Look how cute he is
你看看他　长得多逗人呢
He should be a nice baby to take care of
应该很好带的
说不定他们将来会回来
They may return to take the kid back some day
再把孩子带回去的嘛
孩子
Kid?
打⋯
Beat…
你究竟是何方神圣　快说
Who are you? Speak up
我没有〝摸摸〞嘛
You must know some magic Come on, teach me
你一定会变戏法　快点教我
摸摸⋯
- Milk…    - Stop playing dumb
你还给我装白痴
摸摸⋯
哎⋯〝摸摸〞在那个姐姐身上　快过去拿
Go and get milk from that lady.
Go over
嘿　我看你还能〝盯〞到什么时候　嗨
Let's see how long you can pretend
摸⋯
Milk… no… no milk
没有　没有〝摸摸〞
他还真是个低能儿
He's really retarded. He's not pretending
你们两个摸我的老婆
You two conspired to make fun of my wife?
摸得过不过瘾呢
Satisfied yet?
你去死
Go to hell
快走　走啊　走
- Go on, run    - Brother…
哥哥⋯
Chop you up
老爷　看来你那点银子不够他吃的呀
Master, your pay might not be adequate to sustain him
我得找份兼差才行
I'll need to get a part-time job
我们家附近不是有家孤儿院吗
There's an orphanage near our home
我李茂春才不会做那种事呢
I, Li Mau Cheun, won't do such a thing
他已经懂事多了　东西是吃了不少
He's much wiser now,
though a big eater
我也教了他很多东西
I've also taught him a lot
很快他就可以自食其力了
He'll soon be able to support himself
哎　看着啊　哎⋯叫我
Look
Greet me
〝鲍鱼〞
Abalone
哎呀〝鲍鱼〞是一片一片的　叫我哥哥
Abalone comes in pieces. Call me brother
哎⋯叫她⋯
Greet her
〝知知〞
Little brother
傻冒货〝知知〞是一条一条的
Nonsense! Brother comes in strips
Try again
再叫一次
He's too small to remember
他才那么小　怎么会记得嘛
〝爸爸〞
Bakbak (uncle)
啊⋯他终于叫对了一次了
Now he said it right
屙巴巴
Clean white white
总算缘分一场　尽力而为吧
It's affinity. Let's just do our best
跟他多玩一会好了　我去看看公文
Just play with him for a little while I need to revise some documents
我也去做点刺绣
I must rush my embroidery as well
啊　伏虎罗汉现身
Tiger Fighter Lo Han transfigures
啊⋯阿龙
Ah Lung… where're you?
哎　老兄啊　你到哪儿去了
Brother, we're running out of time
我没什么时间呢　你听着　你是神仙
Listen, you're a fairy
只是你不知道
You don't know…
因为你的天灵盖还没有开
…because your head cover is not yet opened
你记着啊　打雷的时候你把头伸出去
Remember, hold out your head when it thunders
让雷劈开你的天灵盖
Let the thunder split up the cover,
那你就全会记起来了
then you'll revive your memory
是谁在那边穷嚷嚷
Who's making all that noise there?
害得我尿尿断断续续的
Can't even pee in all that chaos
虫虫飞
Count the bugs
The bugs fly
Hurray…
叫什么叫　一定是尿尿了　我看看
So noisy? Must have wet your pants, let me see
扇扇⋯
Fan…
哎　走开嘛
- Keep toying with that lousy fan, really…    - Fan…
真是没得救了　太可怜了
He's hopeless, poor thing
扇扇⋯
Fan…
不是这把
Not this one
大夫　麻烦你帮我看看这家伙
Doctor, please see
还有没有得救
- if he can be treated?    - Milk…
没得救了
- No    - Milk…
哎　了解　我只是没事问问　不好意思
I see,
- just asking, thanks    - Milk…
师傅
Master
黄大富在家出了事　他们都过来了
Wong Dai Fu's having trouble at home,
they're moving him over here
真的　快点
Really? Go quickly then
还有大夫　我⋯
- Doctor, also…    - Milk…
叫什么叫　你他妈的叫春呢
You bitch! Don't point at me
臭婆娘　你这烂皮货
Holy cow!
干吗　不服就上来呀你
- Streaking in the street    - So what?
Never seen before?
Move the whole bed out
啊　马上风
A stroke
想看不会回家看你老妈
- See when it'll be your turn    - What?
你老妈有的我都有
- Yes, I cursed you. Crazy    - Just say so
哎　那不是怡香院的那个小玉吗
So what
可不就是那个贱婆娘吗
Have you no shame, bitch?
光天化日之下干上这种下流的事情嘛
Doing such an immoral thing in broad daylight
可真是有伤风化
How shameful
哎　不收钱让你们看已经是便宜你们了
Hey, we'll get double pay in daylight, don't you know?
这么叽叽歪歪的
Crazy! Consider yourselves lucky
你想怎么样啊你　有种上来呀　哎呀　累死了⋯下来休息一下吧
to watch this for free
Take a rest
嘿　干吗停下来呀　我可是在赶时间呢
Hey, why are we stopping? Hey, I'm in a hurry
幸亏里面那个男人不是我
Luckily it wasn't me,
死得真冤枉啊　啊
- or I'll suffer    - That guy is so unlucky
怎么样　要不要来参观比较一下
Do you like it? Come and have a look
谁丢我
Who did it?
是我丢你
I did
姑娘　可不可以麻烦你端庄一点
Lady, be a bit more decent
什么　装我不会了
I don't have decency
I only have a navel.
不过我正待在那儿
Come and visit us at Yi Heung Brothel
啊　哈　太不知羞耻　当心被雷劈
Shameless, you'll be struck by thunder
哎　有空你们也可以来捧捧场嘛
Hey guys, come and visit me when you have time
刚讲完就要打雷了
What I just said came true! A real thunderbolt
真是老天有眼　劈死她
Heaven has eyes. Strike her
怎么会差那么远
Missed by a mile. Over there
在那一边　看准一点　再来
Aim better. Try again
- Are you OK…    - Alright…
Are you alright…
降龙罗汉现身　下凡普度众生啊
Dragon Fighter has reincarnated in the mortal world to save people
白痴
摸摸⋯
Milk…
伏虎
Tiger Fighter
摸摸
- Milk    - Take her to dip in a pig cage
为了帮我你变成这个样子
You became this just for helping me
太够义气了
You're such a loyal friend
摸摸⋯
Black
干什么你们⋯放开我
- Don't…    - Streaking in the street
is so immoral
九世〝野鸡〞
- A prostitute for 9 lives?    - Scum! Really cheap
- Take her to dip in a pig cage    - Don't
你们大家都是女人　何苦互相残杀呢
You're all women, why fight against each other?
她是〝野鸡〞啊
She's a whore
〝鸡〞都有爱国的嘛
A whore…
…could be patriotic
Right
谢了
Thanks
我会很快回来找你
I'll come back to you very soon
哎　你叫什么名字
Hey, what's your name?
姓名只是代号　怎么叫都一样
A name is just a label, so makes no difference
你看着办吧
Up to you
大哥哥
Big brother
人家在叫你　还不走
She's calling you. Let's go
摸摸⋯
Milk
走了
Get going
摸摸
Milk
走嘞
- Go now    - Milk
摸摸
走了
- Go now    - Milk
(Guo Ching Temple)
妈妈⋯
Milk…
爸爸⋯
摸摸⋯
摸摸
就是这里了
It's here
哎　老兄　我等你好久了
Brother, I waited for you for a long time
你是哪位
Who are you, sir?
土地公啊　这也不能怪你
God of Earth
你的元神还没有回来
I don't blame you. Your Yun San (spirit) has not returned
你不要怕
Don't be frightened! You'll be fine once you get back your golden body
只要你把金身拿回来就没事了
还有啊　你这个金身呢
Also, your golden body…
官府跟强盗都争着要呢
…is sought by both bureaucracy and the underworld
上个月那一次来争的人可多着呢
Most people came last month
你到底是土地公还是老大
Are you God of Earth or local mob?
金身就在这里
The golden body is here
金身就是我　我也⋯
Totally understand! The golden body is me and I am the golden body
你跟我说没用　跟他们说去
No point telling me, tell them instead
哎　对
Yes
哎⋯你们两个头放错了
Your heads have been exchanged
不会吧　先换过来
Really?
Change back first
什么东西
What is it?
木鱼
A wooden fish
鱼
Fish
啊　这也能吃啊
Is this possible?
哎　师傅　打搅你一会儿　容我说两句话
Please spare some time and listen to me
我不认识你
I don't know you
在十三世之前
Thirteenth life cycles ago,
我在这间寺庙当和尚
I was a monk in this temple
到了八世上下我就做了住持了
Then by the eighth life cycles, I became an abbot
也就是这个金身还没有圆寂之前
I was the golden body right there The Sing Ging Abbot before he passed away
性经大师然后升了天做了神了
I then ascended to Heaven and became a fairy Follow me
请跟我来　然后你猜会怎么样
Guess what happened afterwards?
最后就变成一个降龙罗汉
The fairy became Dragon Fighter Lo Han
That's me
也就是我本人
Follow me
这次我下来是办点小事情
I came down on a mission
至于什么事情你就不用管了
As regards what the mission is, you need not know
看你这个德行　资质平常
You are at best a common person
念你在寺里待那么久了
However, considering the length of your service,
没有功劳也有苦劳
you've accumulated some worthiness so I'll give you some face…
在你徒弟面前我就叫你一声师傅
…and address you as master in front of your pupils
够意思吧
还不赶快去拿件衣服给我换去
Should show you due respect
Go get me some clothes to change
师傅　他是疯子
Master, he is mad
可是我一看到他我就很欣赏他
So am I
I admire him on sight.
拿衣服来
- Bring me the clothes    - Yes
是
乖　哈
You're lovely
哇　你怎么那么快就吃光了
You've eaten all of it so quickly?
外面还有一个更大的呢
There's a bigger one outside
这一根是我的宝贝　不能吃的
This is made of steel and can't be eaten
要吃吃后面那个
Eat the drum behind
求你温柔一点　拜托
I beg you not to bite, please
师傅　照惯例帮我取个名吧
Master
Give me a priest name as in the normal procedure
你这么癫　就叫济癫吧
You are so mad, I'll call you Mad Monk
非常好
Very good
救命啊　不要追我
Help! Don't chase me…
九世乞丐
A beggar for 9 lives?
不要啊
Don't
真的好苦啊
Horrible! Really horrible
啊　袁霸天　快躲
What? Yun Ba Tin
Hide quickly
袁霸天来了　先到我家躲一躲　走
Hey, Yun is here!
Hide in my home, quick
土地公
Hey, God of Earth
九世恶人　全都到齐了
A villain of 9 lives?
Save my time
救命啊
Help
我早说不要让我再看到你
I told you not to let me see you
我一看到你　我就火大
A mere sight of you makes me so mad
我也不想让你看到我　你不要过来
I don't want you to see me either. Keep away
我要避开你　但是避不了
I wanted to avoid you, but couldn't
You can hit my head,
你打我的头好了　不要打我的背啊
not the back
好　我把庙也烧了　看你能往哪儿跑
Run? I'll burn down the temple,
see if you can get away
连你这个臭和尚也烧掉
I'll burn you, stinky monk, too
我要烧你　你竟敢吹灭我的火
I want to burn you, how dare you blow out my fire?
你⋯
You…
痛吧
Does it hurt?
我只是让你了解被人欺负的痛苦
Now you know the agony of being bullied
放下屠刀　立地成佛
Lay down the sword and be a Buddha
我不会生气　我疼你　我爱你
Don't be mad! Give you a kiss
重新做人　乖孩子
Take my advice and be a new person
Good boy
不可能　我的娘哎
Impossible…
回去上个厕所想清楚
Think over indoors.
我会很快回来找你的
I'll come to you soon
你不要再行乞了　跟我回家吧
Don't be a beggar anymore. Go home with me
我不要⋯
What a horrible monster
你怕什么
What are you afraid of?
我不去啊
No, I'm not going
走了
Get going
哥哥⋯
啊　哥哥⋯
Brother. Milk… Brother. Milk.
孩子　你怎么弄成这个样子　爸爸
- Son, what happened to you?    - Bakbak
嚯　我换了发型　不错吧
I changed my hairstyle. Not bad, right?
啊　房子怎么也变了样了
What happened to the house?
(Li Sau Yun, I vow to kill your whole family)
(Signed by Yun Ba Tin)
修缘呢　你怎么会惹上袁霸天这种人呢
Sau Yun, why mess with a character like Yun Ba Tin?
屙巴巴⋯
Bakbak
Clean white, white
李修缘　我誓要杀你全家
Li Sau Yun, I vow to kill your whole family
袁霸天留字
Signed by Yun Ba Tin
哎　老爷　他杀光了我们全家的畜牲
Master…, they killed all the poultries,
连蟑螂老鼠都没放过
even rats and roaches
还有只蟑螂是大肚子的　太残忍了
Also includes a pregnant roach, so cruel
哎呀　还好我们跟老爷夫人去拜神了
Luckily you went to the temple with master and madam
这么快就查到我底细　真厉害
Found out my background so soon. Great!
可惜我已经不是李修缘了
Unfortunately I'm not Li Sau Yun anymore
嘿　看不出来他还写了一手好书法
His calligraphy is good, couldn't tell from appearance
连日子都写下了
He even put down the date,
耶嘿　这个家伙做事还挺有条理的
such an organized person
哎呀　家里被人弄成这个样子
Son, look at the mess here,
你还说这些话
yet you're still concerned with such matters
啊　老爷⋯
Master…
你爸爸他不行了
Your dad won't make it
哇　寿终正寝　福气到极点了
Natural death is his good fortune. Let me see,
让我算算　哎哟　下辈子做皇帝啊
he'll be an emperor in his next life. Good for him
已经很不错了
修缘呢　你这孩子　你是不是疯了
Sau Yun…, are you crazy?
对了　现在我的新名字叫济癫
Bingo, my new name is Mad Monk
啊　哎呀　天呢
我们李家是做错了什么事了呀
Heaven, what has our family done wrong?
是啊　你要是没做错事
Yes, if you've done nothing wrong,
我还应该跟他一块儿死才对呀
you should die with him
啊　夫人⋯
Madam…
哎　快拿麝香让夫人闻一闻呢　快
Give her some musk to smell, hurry
哎　别动　他们俩好好的
Don't move
你们就不要多事
Master and madam are fine, you shouldn't fiddle
他们俩是鸳鸯蝴蝶命　死也死一双啊
They're destined to become butterfly lovers,
and they always die together
他们俩在下一辈子将会再续未了情
They'll continue their romance in the next life
真是羡煞旁人呢
How admirable
哎　少爷　那我们该怎么办呢
Young master, what should we do then?
这是喜事　赶快买一只鸡回来庆贺一下
It's an auspicious affair, get a chicken to celebrate
还有你　找个仵作回来送他们一程
And you, get an undertaker to give them a lift
走吧⋯快点⋯
Go… Hurry…
我们快走吧
Let's go quickly
哎　你还不可以走
- You can't go yet    - What?
啊
哎　睡一会儿倒可以
But you can sleep for a while
我⋯
Aiya…
扇扇⋯
Fan…
鸭乖乖⋯
Good duckling… You two've lots of kids,
你们夫妻俩生了这么多
送一只给我吃
why not give me one to fill my stomach
如果我数到三
你们没有摇头那就表示答应了
If you don't shake your head when I count to 3,
一　二　三
that means you consent
1, 2, 3
鸭子
- Aiya    - Outrageous
又是你
You again?
岂有此理
Sunk deep to a duck thief?
不要过来⋯
You keep away! Keep away…
我问过它们夫妻俩了
I got the couple's consent
你问过它们
Did you ask?
它们问过你吗
Did he ask you?
没有　没有
No…
啊　鸭子怎么会说话
What? Ducks can speak too?
你还有什么话说
What more do you have to say?
你不要再拉我了
Stop pulling me…
一定是它妈妈勾引那只九官鸟
His mother must've seduced a parrot that's why he could speak
它才会说话
哎　对了　一定是勾引了九官鸟
His mother has seduced a parrot?
人家的妈妈勾引什么人是它的事
That's totally up to his mother
什么时候要你来管　我告诉你
Who asked you to meddle in it? I tell you,
我们做人处世一定要有点自尊
we must have self-respect as a human
既然你想吃它们
If you want to eat them, you must get their consent first
得先得到它们同意啊
哪有人情愿被别人吃的
Who would consent to being eaten?
他妈的
Damn
我现在想吃你们
I want to eat you now Whoever's willing can come with me
哪个愿意的　可以跟我走　哼
哎哟　我⋯我崇拜你啊
So great
可以叫我一声师傅了吧
Worth to greet me as Master?
师傅　有什么我可以效劳的
Master, what can I do for you? Just let me know
请尽管吩咐
晚了　你该睡了
It's late, you should sleep
啊　师傅　你怎么把我当猪
Master, I am like a pig. I only sleep in daylight
一看到我就叫我睡觉
大种　你老爸来找你了
Dai Jung, your dad is here for you
你妈才来找你呢　我老爸早死了
Your mom found you. My dad died a long time ago
你看一看嘛
Have a look
啊　老爸　你好吗
Dad, how are you?
大种　你听不听老爸的话
Won't you listen to dad?
听
Yes
哎　听⋯我就以老爸的名义跟你说
Then I advise you in dad's name,
以后不准再托钵行乞
never go begging again with your bowl
老爸　我也是这么想啊
Dad, I've long yearned for this
我应该换一个大盆子再去要饭
I want to get a bigger bowl to beg
啊　哼　你他妈的
Outrageous
刚刚我只记得老爸骂了我一顿
Just now my dad came to see me
然后就走了
哎　先吃点东西吧
Enough, go in and take a rest
我被这家店里人赶出来过
May be thrown out by the waiter
哇　这么多金子
Lots of gold
抱好
Carry them
这样子就不会被赶出来了
Then you won't be thrown out
哇　大爷　请坐　请坐
Sir, this way please
哎呀　臭和尚　滚出去
Get out, you stinking monk
哎
啊　哎　两位大爷　请坐　请坐
Sir, this way please
您先坐会儿　我去给您沏茶　啊
Have a seat. I'll get some nice tea for you
哎　好⋯
大种　喜欢吃什么就点　啊
What would you like to eat? Tell them
我喜欢吃鸡屁股
I want chicken butts
鸡你妈个屁股
Damn your ass!
你现又有钱又有面子
You have money now,
当然是先来碗鱼翅漱漱口
you should order sharks’ fins to rinse your mouth
哦　好啊
Yes, right
好就叫啊
Order then
我不敢叫　还是你叫
Hey, I dare not. You order for me
哎呀　你连这一点自信心都没有
You lack confidence even in this,
怎么出人头地　鼓起勇气来
how are you going to be successful?
Summon your courage
给我两天时间考虑一下
Give me 2 days to consider
你耍我是不是　说
Making fun of me? Speak
给我一碗鱼翅
I want…
我要你大声地说　连街坊都听得到
Louder, I want everyone to hear it
给我一碗鱼屎
Give me a bowl of butts…
不是屎　是翅
Not butts, sharks' fins
你不要逼我
Don't force me…
别傻了　我怎么会逼你呢
Don't be silly! Why would I do that?
乖乖地说不就没事了嘛
Just say it and everything will be alright
要听话　啊
Do as I say
我只想吃鸡屁股
But I really want to eat chicken butts
我一定要你说
Damn it! Fought back!
I insist you say…
你说　说　给我一碗鱼翅漱漱口
…give me a bowl of sharks' fins to rinse my mouth. Say it
给我一碗鱼翅漱漱口
Give me a bowl of sharks’ fins to rinse my mouth…
你个王八蛋　你　啊
You bastard
好好吃
- Yummy    - Outrageous
气死我　你个臭小子
大种　废话我不想多说了
Dai Jung, I won't talk any more nonsense
看我的
Look
这是我本来的面目　降龙罗汉
This is my real self, Dragon Fighter Lo Han
有鬼呀
Ghost
少鸡猫子喊叫了　鬼不是这样子
Stop screaming! A ghost is not like this
鬼是这样子的
It's like this
哎　你不会是真的昏过去了吧
Have you really passed out?
哎哟　谁踢我嘴巴
Who's hitting my mouth?
装神弄鬼
Disguised yourself in a white top,
披个被单还挂两条猪肠在嘴上
and hung two sausages on your mouth
just to scare a beggar?
来吓乞丐　白吃屎啊你
You're a beast!
Go to hell…
哎⋯别那么冲动嘛⋯
- Stop it    - Don't stop me
Let's go
这种人会修理他的嘛
- Go to hell    - Don't be impetuous
就是
- Let's go    - Don't be mad
神经病啊他　大白天来吓人呢
- For such nuts, you've to beat him to death    - Let's go
现在的人真的不怕鬼啊
People nowadays aren't frightened of ghosts
Dai Jung
大种　你终于明白了吧
Don't you understand now?
你真的是神仙
Are you really a fairy?
如假包换　所以你有什么愿望
100%
我都可以帮你实现
If you have any wishes, just let me know,
尽管跟我说
I can fulfill them for you. Tell me
我要你带我上天堂
I want you to take me to Heaven
你真会想
What a fantastic wish
我不要再做什么大种乞丐了
I don't want to beg over here…
any more
啊　终于让我看到你的自尊心了
At last I see you have pride
I want to be…
我要做一个神仙乞丐
…a God of Beggars
哈⋯你妈呀
Outrageous…
明天有早课　大家早一点去休息
There'll be morning orisons tomorrow,
师傅　外面那个乞丐怎么办
let's rest early
Master, what to do with the beggar outside?
我佛慈悲　寺院大开方便之门
Buddha is merciful and the temple is to serve people
就让他在外面睡一个晚上好了
Let him stay outside for one night
摸摸⋯
Milk…
快把木鱼法器搬到里面去
Hurry! Take them all inside
摸摸⋯
Hey, you get the stuff
鱼鱼⋯
Milk… Fish… Ya… Fish…
臭小子
Walk faster
哥哥⋯
Brother… Milk…
生个叉烧都比生你好　臭小子
Bad boy, bearing a piece of BBQ pork is better than having you
叉烧
BBQ pork?
不是我　我很臭　不能吃啊
No…
BBQ pork…
不是我　我很臭　不能吃啊
I'm stunk! Don't eat me.
哎呀　伏虎罗汉现真身
Tiger Fighter Lo Han transfigures
你吃我豆腐
Insulting me?
我被你吓得尿裤子
You scared the piss out of me
麒麟怪　你怎么搞成这样子
Unicorn, why look so miserable?
我弄成这个样子是为了掩人耳目
I dressed up to hide my identity,
下来给你报信的
so I can come down to inform you
什么事
What's up?
你今天私自下凡　上面已经知道了
Heaven knew you've come down to the mortal world,
还派了瘟神下来　到处散播瘟疫
so they sent down the God of Plague to spread disease everywhere
到时候伤了多少人　死了多少人
You'll bear the consequence of
全算在你的头上
the casualties caused
哼　你在这里造这么多的孽
For the evil done, by that time,
你回去的时候一定会被连降三级
you may be demoted 3 grades.
你死定喽
伏虎　你醒过来了
Wake up again, Tiger Fighter
哎　降龙啊　这件事情不关我的事啊
Dragon Fighter, this is not my fault
虽然不关你的事
Though it might not be,
你又不是不知道上面那票笨蛋
you know what it's like with the fools up there
一个人降级不要紧
It matters little if one is downgraded,
还要害了这么多条人命
but to harm so many lives,
这下你可麻烦了　就是嘛
it's really big trouble
就是啊
That's right…
也不晓得是什么规矩
What rule is that?
你告诉我　是哪个下令放瘟疫的
Tell me, who ordered the plague to spread?
上头嘛
A high directive
他妈的⋯
Damn it
哎　上头什么人呢
Hey, which department?
啊　哎　说呀　我不会讲是你说的
Tell us,
we promise not to accuse you
是康乐部啊
The Recreation Department
嗯　康乐部是搞旅游的
What? They are responsible for travel though
康乐部跟会计部有挂钩的嘛
They are linked to the Accounts Department
哎　会计部是发薪水的
- The Accounts Department pays salaries only    - Yes
是啊
没错啊
That's right
糟糕的就是会计部跟宣传部
The trouble is the Accounts and
都是拜把兄弟
Advertising Departments are brothers,
又好像宣传部跟福利部
then Publicity Department…
大家都死要面子⋯
- Ignore him … and Welfare Department…
哎　降龙　别理他　我回到上面去了啊
Hey, ah Lung,
- I'm going up now    - …have to show respect to each other
你自己小心点　保重啊
- Take care    - Also Publishing Department…
claimed that we're brothers…
上去认个错　看有没有办法补救
Apologize to see if there's any remedy
保重啊
- Be careful    - Health Department… They…
哎　走了
- Let's go! Genital In short they screw up together…
那你就丑大啰　你说是不是
This is most disastrous… do you agree?
哎　一夜之间死了一百多个人呢
Over a hundred died in one night
哎　一定是有妖精作怪
An evil spirit must be behind this
死乞丐　生那么多大毒疮
Damn beggar,
早晚毒死你
why not die yet for having so many sores
啊　你这里更大耶
- Wow    - What?
Yours is worse
Shit…
大毒疮⋯完了⋯这下完蛋了
Sores… I've sores…
I've got big sores… I'm finished…
不用怕　多生几粒你都不会死
Don't worry, more sores still won't kill you
降龙、齐天大圣　至霸尊者驾到
Dragon Fighter…
…the Supreme of Monkey King is here
我知道这里有瘟疫
I know there's a plague here,
我就踏上西天跟玉皇大帝谈判
so I negotiated with the Heavenly Emperor
他说要你们凑足一千两白银给我
He told you to raise 1,000 taels.
让我做法事　替你们消灾解难
I'll perform a ceremony…
…to avert the disaster
我做这场法事　可能要我减寿十年呢
Doing this ceremony
may shorten my life by 10 years
妖言惑众　打搅我睡觉
Spreading misleading fallacies, you're disturbing my sleep
你⋯
Why, you…
什么你⋯
What… I do this to save people's lives
我这么做是为了拯救苍生啊
要我减寿十年我也在所不计
I don't mind even if my life is shortened for ten years
你们知不知道
还掰
Still talking?
牺牲很大的呀
It's a big sacrifice, you know?
就这么牺牲啊
How big is the sacrifice?
至少我少活十年呢
There's one more mole…
Yes… Yes what?
你再〝盯〞啊　把你屁股变到嘴巴上去
Again! Let me stick your ass to your mouth
救你们唯一的方法呢
- Three times a day,    - There's one way
啊　一天只能三次　算你走运了　帮你找一个人出来祭神呢
- lucky you    - to save your life,
get someone to sacrifice to the gods
那要找哪种人呢
Who…
是啊　到哪儿去找
这个人是专门去送死的
One to whom life means nothing
啊⋯送死⋯到哪儿去找⋯
Where to find one…
哎　怡香院里多的是
You can find many at Yi Heung Brothel
Yes…
Let's go…
啊　哎　老鸨
Boss
哟　这班臭男人怎么这么早就来了
- Those lousy men come so early?    - Yes…
就是
快⋯叫她们交出一个人来　啊　快点⋯
- What if they won't agree?    - Go in…
如果她们不肯交人那怎么办呢
哎　这关乎全城人的安危
This concerns the safety of the whole city, they have no choice
由不得她们不肯了
大家一起进去　地保　你先走啊　快⋯
Let's go in together. Chief, you go first
什么事
- What happened?    - Go…
停
你们搞什么鬼啊
Freeze! What's the matter?
天爷　你也知道
这次瘟疫死了那么多的人
Master Tin, you know, the plague has killed a lot of people
关我怡香院什么事
What has it to do with my Yi Heung Brothel?
他们说随便找几个姑娘去祭神
They want to get some girls as sacrifices
干吗不找你妈去祭呀
Why don't you send your mother?
是啊
昨天你不是告诉我很讨厌你老婆
That's right You told me you hated your wife last night
叫她去呀
Why don't you send her?
哎　天爷　你很为难　嚯
Master Tin, I know it's a hard decision for you
我有什么为难的　这里全是我的人
Why? They are all mine
要她死就死　要生就生　对不对
Their lives are in my hands
Right?
哎　对
That's right…
啊　哪几个没人要的　统统给我站出来
Take those ones who nobody wants
我可以省点米饭
站出来　快⋯快点　站出来
I can save some costs
哎　用不了那么多　一个半个就够了
No need for so many, one is more than enough
哎　出来围一圈　围一圈⋯快点⋯
- Come and form a circle…    - So bad…
围好⋯围个圈啊　快点⋯围好了⋯
- Hurry… Quick! Come…    - Outrageous…
驼子躺下
哎　好
Hunchback, lie down
他的脚趾向谁就是谁了
Whoever his toe points to, will be the one
- Turn…    - So scary…
哦　你耍赖
You're cheating
哦⋯你⋯不是我⋯
Not me…
Take her away
走⋯拉到祭坛去⋯走⋯
Not me! You've seen it
哎　你记不记得你昨天跟我说过什么
- Get going    - Take her away
Remember what you said to me yesterday?
我说你收费太高啊　走⋯
I said you charged a high price. Move
Cut the crap, take her away
不是我
嗯　敢在我怡香院撒野　嗯
You dare create trouble here?
不⋯不是我
No! No… Not me…
怎么祭
Hey, how should the sacrifice be offered?
哎　红烧
Braise
给我留点时间
- It'll take a long time then    - Not me…
你们先等着　留只左腿给我
Leave the left leg for me I'll take a rest
我先歇会儿
抓她去沐浴更衣　走
Clean her up and get changed. Go
不要啊
No…
哇　好漂亮　烧死了多可惜
She's so beautiful. What a waste to burn her?
赶快想办法救她
Find a way to save her
漂亮的才救　烧你就不用救了
To help only the pretty one?
If so, I won't save you then
哎　你这把扇子
Your… your fan has to wait until dawn for its power to return?
真的要等到天亮了才能变东西啊
与其等到天亮
Rather than wait until dawn,
倒不如等我的法力消失好了
better off to wait till my powers are gone
喂　我解释给你听你就会明白了
Go
You'll understand once I explain to you
不明白　我就是不明白
No need. I don't understand anyway
我⋯照我吩咐做　烧啊⋯
Just do as I say
吉时已到
The auspicious time has come
哎　慢一点　请问一下
Wait! How you know that
你怎么知道烧死了她就会没有瘟疫呢
burning her will stop the plague?
哎⋯玉帝托梦告诉我的
- Heavenly Highness told me in a dream    - Oh…
王母娘娘刚刚托梦告诉我
Queen Mother told me to burn…
说烧你娘呀
- …your mother in a dream    - It can't be…
啊　你⋯
还说要连骂三次
And if I scold you three times,
你脸上那两块黑痣就会没有了
the two moles on your face will disappear
神经病　走开
You are crazy, go away
时间到了　快骂
It's time, scold him
我⋯我不要
I dare not
烧啊⋯
〝离〞你⋯我〝离〞你
Bastard, bastard, bastard
啊⋯不见了⋯好灵啊⋯是啊⋯
It really works…
你们看他的脸　比神仙还要灵验
Look at his face, more divine than god
哎　各位　他已经跟王母娘娘谈好了
Everyone, he has made an agreement with Queen Mother,
以后不会再有瘟疫了　马上放人
there'll be no more plague
Release her now
如果放了她　还有瘟疫那怎么办呢
What if there'll be plague again after she is released?
对啊⋯还有瘟疫怎么办⋯怎么办⋯
Right…
What to do? Tell me…
我不知道⋯不知道啊
None of my business! Don't! I don't know
哎　这样子了
Can't release her
要是烧死她还有瘟疫的话　就烧死你们
However, if the plague still persists after she's burnt to death
I'll burn you all
哎⋯听到没有　马上放人
Hear that? Release her now
哎　火这么大怎么放啊
The fire is so fierce. How to release?
拿水来浇熄它
Bring some water to put it out
街口的井给封了　哪来的水呀
The well nearby is blocked. Where can we find water?
没有水　随便什么水都可以
Any kind of water will do
哦　我明白了
Got it
嗯　你实在太神勇了　避都不避啊
You're so bold, you don't even flinch
口水嘛　又不是没吃过
It's just saliva, no need to be scared
谢谢你
Thank you
不客气
My pleasure
I…
你休息一下
Take a rest
哎　你不要走
Don't go
你放心　那些人不会再来烧你了
Don't worry, they won't burn you again
那些臭男人平时在床上都对我那么好
Those lousy men were nice to me when in bed
他们干吗要放火来烧我
Why did they want to burn me to death?
原因是这样子的
It's simple Those men who come to you,
那些人来找你　就跟坐马桶一样
treat you like a shit-bowl
坐的时候固然是很舒坦
They feel comfortable when sitting on it,
但是绝对不会对马桶有感情的
but they're not emotionally tied to it
我不明白
What do you mean?
也就是说　请你以后不要再做马桶了
That is… to say, never be a shit-bowl anymore Get it?
明白吗
我明白了
Yes
你干什么
What are you doing?
我要报答你呀
I want to repay you
哎　不要　你真是〝鸡〞性难改耶
Don't! Your whorish nature is incorrigible
我不收你钱的呀
It's free
你不收钱　我还收呢
Big brother, you don't charge,
but I do
你连马桶都不如
Worse than a shit-bowl
你除了会躺下收钱之外
What else can you do besides lying down for money?
你还会做什么
嗯　倒挂也行　不会吧
You can do it upside down? No way…
哎呀　妈的　我怎么会跟你谈这个玩意儿
I don't mean that
我是说你可不可以换一个职业
What I mean is can you find another job…
譬如说卖卖豆腐也行啊
…like selling bean curd?
那摊子摆门口还是床边啊
Should I put the stall at the door or beside the bed?
你⋯
师傅⋯要到半块豆腐乳
Master… I got half a piece of preserved bean curd
哇　嗯　好香啊　有没有我的份
Smells good, any for me?
豆腐乳你自己吃好了
Keep the bean curd for yourself
哎　别这样　连汤都喝光了
Oh no, finish the sauce too
是条洋狗　没什么味
It's a foreign dog, not much taste
还有一口　我试试就知道了
There's one left. Try and I'll know
哎　这只狗生前咬死了两个人
This dog has bitten two people to death before
我现在吃它是超度它
Eating it means I'm honoring its dead spirit
你想吃　你还没这个本事呢
You're not qualified yet to eat it
哎　不会吧　师傅
Not really, Master.
狗肉穿肠过　徒弟的肚子好饿
Your pupil is very hungry
做做好事嘛　要留块骨头给我尝尝
Be kind enough to leave me at least a piece of bone
拜托
Please… be kind… please…
拜托嘛　师傅　拜托
别闹了
Go away
不就根毛吗　好了嘛　好了　拜托⋯
Be kind! Hey! Why not? Hey
拜托拜托嘛⋯我知道你还没有吞下去
Don't play! I know you haven't swallowed it
不要闹了嘛
你这个臭小子　除了要饭你还会什么　师傅　你给我一块嘛
You bastard,
how come you ain't that persistent apart from begging?
你这个臭小子　除了要饭你还会什么　师傅　你给我一块嘛
Help… C'mon…
师傅
师傅　你看
I need to get the rack.
出来了⋯
哎　记得下次再来
Remember to get back your underpants
换我了
Get it
哎　内裤拿走了没
拿了⋯
快点　你欢玩了　换我了啦
Why took so long? It's my turn.
来⋯
Come
小玉
Yuk
哎　怎么是你
It's you
你不但不听我的话　还变本加厉
You aren't listening to me and get even worse now
简直太不自爱
You have no self-respect at all
我全照你的吩咐做了
I've done as you told me
哎　你这个妓女就跟小贩一样当街叫卖
You are simply hawking yourself in the street
还好意思说照我的吩咐做
How dare you say you're doing as I said
没错　我是在卖豆腐
Wrong! I'm selling bean curd…
哇　真的卖豆腐咯
Really?
哎　快一点　你到底做不做生意了
Hurry up, are you doing business or not?
说好了干一次才跟你买豆腐的
We agreed to do once for buying a bowl of bean curd
不干是吧　退钱啊
No? Give me back the money…
别生气嘛　走⋯
No… I'll do it… Coming…
哎⋯来⋯
多谢你的提醒啊
Thanks for your advice
我现在的生意好得不得了呢
My business is good now
啊　哦　她是改了　只是用错方法了
She's willing to change, just in the wrong way
大种　跟我来
Dai Jung, follow me
师傅　你以后不要在小玉的面前
Hey… help… Please do me a favor
Don't mention my nickname here. Thanks
或者是她的豆腐摊前面叫我的名字
my nick name here. Thanks
行不行
我叫你什么名字
What did I call you?
大种乞丐
Beggar Dai Jung
你叫大种吗
Is your name Beggar Dai Jung?
别忘了你叫朱大常　你这臭小子
Your name is Chow Yat Cheung… Go to hell…
Don't beat me…
不要打⋯你要打带我到后面巷子再打
If you want to beat me, let's go to the back alley
在这儿打我会让人家看到的
Beat freely. Siu Yuk will see us here
我带你到后面巷子去啊
I'll show you the way
哦　原来要在小玉面前
So your pride will only appear
你的自尊心才会出现
in the presence of Siu Yuk
我明白了
I got it
哦　好爽哦
Got it
谁说他们没有救
Who says they have no remedy? They all have remedy
所有的人都可以救
上面的人听着　我赢定了
Listen, fairies above, I'll surely win
I won't marry any man except him in this world
你坏坏　偷看人家洗澡
You're naughty, you peeping-tom
嗯　你才坏呢　不许你这样说我
Bad boy, I forbid you to say this
就是这个造型
This is the style
一个好女孩本来就是应该这个样子
A decent girl should be like this
不会痛嘛　我就知道是在做梦
Not hurt? I know it's a dream
不然我怎么会穿这种衣服
Or else this couldn't have happened
可以的
You can
嗯　这什么虫啊　长得真难看呢
What's it? So ugly…
哎　你看
Look
哇　真漂亮
So beautiful…
小玉　既然毛虫可以变蝴蝶
Yuk, since a caterpillar can become a butterfly,
那么〝鸡〞一样可以变凤凰啊
a chicken… can also become a phoenix
那我要做凤凰　行不行
I want to be a phoenix, can I?
凤凰
A phoenix?
主公　你真有先见之明
Lord, you have good foresight
那个和尚做的一切正如你所说的
That monk has done all that you anticipated
你有什么吩咐　尽管说
If you need anything, just tell me
(Yi Heung Brothel)
嫖妓　改天吧
Call a whore? Maybe another day
我没空
I have no time
我推你是可以　你敢推我　你给我过来
I can push you, but you push me back… come here
不要打我
Don't hit me
厕所上过了　你又不用洗澡
You've gone to the toilet, and you don't need a bath
你还有什么事要做
What else do you need to do?
可是嫖妓干我什么事
But calling a whore… I don't know how
小玉正在上面等她的意中人
Siu Yuk is waiting for her lover upstairs
啊　是谁呀
Who is it?
他叫朱大常
His name is… Chow Yat Cheung
啊　我
Me?
一个风度翩翩的美男子
A good-looking and presentable man
Yeah…
大种　你要切记
Dai Jung, you must remember to leave on the 1st watch
初更时你一定要走
要不然黄金变狗屎
Otherwise, gold will turn back to dog shit,
所有的大疱都会冒出来
吓死别人就不好了
and the sores will emerge again
It'd be bad to scare people away
哎　有没有相熟的姑娘啊
Do you have any familiar lady in mind?
小玉
Siu Yuk
她的大姨妈来了
She is having her period
哎呀　她的大姨妈刚走啊
Her period has just ended
不过她住在这儿不接客的耶
She's only a temporary lodger here, not taking any client
哎呀　不要紧　她偶尔客串一下
Never mind,
你跟我来吧
she sometimes makes guest appearances
Sir, follow me
小玉
Siu Yuk
叫我凤凰
Call me Phoenix
这位官人呢
Sir, how about I order the kitchen to cook
不如我吩咐厨房给你弄几个小菜吧
some dishes for you?
哎　你喜欢吃什么
What would you like?
要是有一盘鸡屁股那就正点了
A plate of chicken butts would be nice
是不是我说错话了
Anything wrong?
真会吃
You're an epicure
你是干哪一行的
What do you do?
要饭的
- I'm a beggar    - What?
哦　哎呀　原来是你
So it's you
你不会嫌弃我吧
Do you mind?
怎么会呢
我看到你就好像看到那个一样
Why would I? When I see you it's like seeing that guy
那个呢
Where's that guy?
是那个叫我来找你的
That guy asked me to come
那个叫你来找我什么事啊
Why did he ask you to come?
那个叫我来找你⋯
That guy asked me here to…
买豆腐
…buy bean curd
哎哟　你坏死喽
You're so naughty
哦　来得正好　顺便把你解决
Good! I'll fix you too
有少林达摩祖师上身
With the possession of Shaolin Patriarch Dharma, in a lamp’s time,
一盏灯的时间
没有理由摆不平你　站住
there's no reason I can't fix you
Halt
干掉他
Sock him
是⋯
Yes
发生什么事了⋯我们过去看看⋯
What happened… Look… what happened?
达摩祖师果然厉害
Really powerful
嗯　达摩　达摩祖师果然厉害
嗯　达摩
Patriarch Dharma?
哼　怕了吧
Are you scared?
看你这个德行　无恶不作　罪孽深重
You are deep in sin
当我做件善事
Consider this as doing charity,
带你回去做和尚重新做人
I'll take you back to be a monk
去你的妈
Damn you
打到你去
I'll beat you till you come with me
开我的玩笑　藤条
Joking… A rattan cane
Look down on me?
小看我
Scared now?
妈的　好累呀
I'm tired
Go…
看你往哪儿跑
See where you can run to?
他妈的二百五　教不会的
Damn it! Never listen
服不服气
- Reconciled to defeat yet?    - Reconciled to the hell of you
服你的妈
原来你就是神仙呢
So, that guy is a fairy?
我还以为你知道
I thought you knew
不好意思　让你费这么大劲儿
Sorry for troubling you
没关系　我喜欢
Never mind. I enjoy it…
多买几块吧
How many?
这种情况两块就够了
For a situation like this, two will suffice
记得跟那个说　明天我会加卖豆浆啊
Remember to tell that guy I'll sell soy milk
as well tomorrow
真的
Really?
你猜那个喜欢吃甜的还是咸的呀
Do you think he'll like it salty or sweet?
咸的
Salty
那加点榨菜吧
Best to add some preserved savory vegetables
放点芝麻更香
Even better with sesame seeds
罗汉蘸豆浆
Lo Han soy milk
他喜欢吃狗肉
He likes dog meat
狗肉罗汉蘸豆浆
Dog meat Lo Han soy milk
Yeah…
锵⋯小玉无敌豆浆霸
Siu Yuk's unbeatable soy milk
耶
Yeah…
哎呀　我是来嫖妓的
I've come for a whore
事到如今　我只好以暴制暴
As matters stand, I have to fight violence with violence
铁头功
Iron Head
认输了吧
Reconciled to defeat now?
叫你当和尚　又不叫你去死
I only want you to be a monk, not go to hell
马上乖乖跟我回去
Be good and come with me now
你真是冥顽不灵啊
You're simply incorrigible
算了　不做和尚好了
OK… forget about being a monk
总之不能杀人　行不行
Just refrain from killing people, okay?
他妈的　到底是人还是禽兽
Damn! Are you a human being or a beast?
觉得怎么样
Do you like me?
好〝黄〞啊
I do
But, make it next life
This life, I have to marry that guy
没想到我们磨了一个晚上的豆浆
You're right. I found my self-respect
还这么开心
after knowing him too
今天晚上算我怕你了
OK, you're on the upside tonight
一人让一步
Let's compromise! If you back off
只要你现在不要去找小玉的麻烦
and leave Siu Yuk alone tonight,
我们的账以后再算
we'll settle our score later
哇　要是我没变身就被你刺死了
If I hadn't changed to Patriarch Dharma, I'd have been killed by you
你这个混球
You bastard
我忍无可忍了
Can't bear with it anymore
我佛慈悲　大吉大利
Buddha is merciful! Good luck
啊　丑了　大种　时辰到了
Shit! Dai Jung, it's time
有人卖大粽子
Is someone selling rice dumplings?
每天都有人来卖粽子　别理他
That stand's there every day.
- Never mind it    - OK
法术全用完了　快走啊
Magic is over! Let's go
糟糕　时辰到了
Shit! Time is up
哎呀　嗯　我怎么又变回乞丐了
Aiya… I changed back to a beggar
你还什么样　你本来就是乞丐啊
Why shout? You are in fact a beggar
哎　不行啊　我要走了
I have to go
喂　我们是好朋友嘛
Hey, are we good friends?
哎呀　还不下来
Why haven't you come down yet… you really…
哎　臭小子　有没看到一个大胡子
Hey man
Have you seen someone with a big beard?
有　他好像在大便呢
Yes, he seems over there in the toilet
追
After him
站住
Halt
臭小子　你好面熟啊
Man, you look familiar
两位壮士　你们认错人了
Heroes, you're mistaken
嗯　你⋯
早叫你不要被我看到了
Outrageous!
看到你我就火大
I warned you not to let me see you
Don't…
你还想白吃啊
Sponge as well?
没有　我没有白吃　我有钱
No, I didn't
I have money
Shit! The gold changed…
不要打了　求你不要打了
他没有白吃　你不要打了
Don't beat him! He's not a sponger
他⋯他算是我男朋友
He's my boyfriend
真下贱　满身疮你都要　啊
That cheap? You even want one with sores?
看我的
Look
老大　早跟你说不是我
Big brother, I told you it wasn't me
你还不承认
You still deny it?
说不定只是长得很像而已嘛
Don't be mad! Maybe it's just likeness
他根本在装神弄鬼
You're pretending
我怎么有胡子嘛
Do I look like that moustached Singh?
刮了行不行
Maybe you shaved it off?
哪有人刮得那么快的
Who could do it so quickly?
哼　你胳膊肘子朝外拐
You're siding with a stranger
我讲道理啊
I talk sense
去死吧
Go to hell
你打伤人了嘛
打伤人又怎么样
See! You've hurt someone
你成心跟我过不去
What? Getting mad?
连老大的话都不听
What? Should I stand here and let you hit me?
哼　谁叫你大欺小
What? You dare disobey what the big brother tells you to do?
What? A big one bullies a small one?
我告诉你　我忍你很久了
- I've endured for a long time.    - Go to hell
喂⋯哎⋯不要打我老大⋯滚啊　你们
Don't beat my big brother! Go away
你滚吧
哎⋯不要打了⋯别打了⋯
Damn it! Again! Don't… Hey…
不要　救命啊
Don't
Help
哎　大爷　不要啊
Don't, master
让你开开眼界
求你放了她吧　大爷
Let her go, please, master
Siu Yuk…
小玉
救我
Help
我跟你拼了
Big head
大种
Dai Jung
哎哟　吓死我了
你进来怎么不敲门呢
Why didn't you knock?
哎　对不起啊　我找错人了
Sorry, I got the wrong place
记着关门啊　来　吃香蕉
Close the door
Have a banana
哎　对不起⋯
Sorry…
师傅　我⋯
Master…
这么久也不下来　找死
What's taken you so long? Wanna die?
都变回乞丐了　快点走啊
Things changed back to the original! Let's go
Master, I can't move
走不动
啊　袁霸天
What? Yun Ba Tin
大种乞丐　赶紧死吧
Go to hell, Beggar Dai Jung
不要叫我大种　叫我朱大常
Don't call me Dai Jung
Call me Chow Yat Cheung
大种
Dai Jung
You've made us suffer a lot
大种　你不能死　要撑下去啊　大种
Dai Jung… you can't die!
You must hang on
大种　你不能死　要撑下去啊　大种
Dai Jung… you can't die! Dai Jung
你没有法术了吗　嗯
You've no more magical powers?
明天有　明天你就知道厉害了
Tomorrow, I'll show you tomorrow
撒谎呢
王八蛋
Kill you, son of a bitch
把他脸反过来
- Turn his face over    - Turn his face
转过去⋯过去　再过去　看好
Look
把眼睛睁开
Open his eyes
哎　滚吧
Master Tin said to let you go, but be careful in future
天爷说放你一马　你以后当心点
刚才看得真爽　眼睛都不眨一下啊
What a show it was just now You didn't even blink
不过刚才真的精采呀
Frankly… it was fascinating
Yes
这一次你还不死啊
You'll surely die this time
土地公⋯快点出来　你给我出来
God of Earth
God of Earth, where are you? Come out quickly
哎⋯我不是来了嘛　干吗大呼小叫的
Hey… I'm here. Why shouting so loud?
要怎么样才可以救大种啊
How can I save Dai Jung?
人的生死早有定数
A man's fate is pre-determined One can't change Heaven's rules
天条规定改不了的
哎呀　大种这次枉死
But he has suffered an innocent death because of me
我无论如何都要救他
I've got to bring him back no matter what
快点帮我想想办法
Help me to think of some ways
枉死一定是下地狱
An innocent death means going to hell
阎罗王这个人没得商量　不过⋯
King of Hades is strict
But…
不过什么
Speak up
入枉死城之前
Before entering the City of Innocent Deaths,
有一段是邪神黑罗煞的地盘
There's an area governed by evil god Hak Lo Sat
他是专收孤魂野鬼的
He admits stray spirits
到了他的手上就永不得超生
Anyone in his hands never gets reincarnated
不过他是可以商量啰
But you may talk it over with him
哎　快点带我下去见见他
Bring me down to him quickly
哎呀　我只是一个小神　没有资格下去
Hey… I'm only a junior god and thus not eligible to go down
不像你　你有金身护着
Unlike you, you've a golden body for protection
上上下下都没问题
which makes you invulnerable
我马上把金身拿回来
I'll go and get the golden body back now
哎⋯千万不可以拿金身来开玩笑啊
Hey… don't make fun of the golden body
不行也得行
I must do what's necessary
干什么
哎呀　放手
What're you doing? Let go
师傅说　这个金身不能离开这间寺庙
Master said this golden body cannot leave the temple
哎呀　离开了又怎么样
What if it does?
不知道
- I don't know    - Then that means it's okay
那就是没事情
借来用用　最多付你利息
Let me borrow it, I'll pay you lots of interest
不可以
- No    - For just one night
只借一个晚上
不行
- No    - One hour
一个时辰
不行
- No    - OK, then a cross
那就把你变个大字
不行　啊　怎么变
What cross?
大黑鬼　你给我站住
Hey man, halt
Stand still
什么事
What's the matter?
放了他
Let him go
你是如来佛祖吗
Are you the Buddha?
不是
No
我呸
Damn
大黑鬼　你真没礼貌
Man, you're so rude. Let me tell you
我告诉你　我跟佛祖是好朋友
I'm friends with the Buddha
我代表他取回这个人的三魂七魄
I'll retrieve this person's spirit on his behalf,
听懂了没有
understand?
哎呀　你好大的胆子　不要过来⋯
How dare you? Stop
Stop
垃圾　叫释迦牟尼来见我
Rubbish! Ask Sakyamuni to see me
不要走
Don't go…
其实我跟佛祖也不太熟
In fact, I'm not on good terms with Buddha
我也不知道你跟他有过节
I didn't know you and he had a grudge
这样子好了　我叫你老大
I'll take you for big brother
你已经有这么多的手下
多一个不多　少一个不少
Since you've so many men under you, having one more doesn't make a difference
这个就当送给我好了
This one… treat this as a gift to me
送给你有什么好处啊
What's in it for me?
好处
What's in it?
哎哟　我帮你修下脚趾甲　好长啊
How about… I'll pedicure for you, the nails are so long,
好不好
okay?
滚开
除非拿你的金身来换
Damn! Unless you exchange it with your golden body
金身　金身不可以给你
Golden body? I can't give it to you
况且你要来也没什么用啊
Besides, you've no use for it
摆着看也好啊
Just as a display
王八蛋　你个死黑鬼　好　换了
Bastard, you're going too far
Okay, exchange
大种　我再怎么样也要带你回去
Dai Jung, I must bring you back by any means
放心好了
Don't worry
把你金身留下来
Put down your golden body
你答应我要交换的
You promised to exchange with me
你居然还吸他的魂魄
Why have you taken his spirit?
我坏嘛
I'm a baddie
臭和尚　你跟鬼一样
Stinking monk, why appeared so sudden
从哪儿冒出来的
糟了　又回到上面来了
Damn, I'm back
你不喜欢的话　就回到下面去好了
If you don't like it, you can go back down
没有金身　我怎么回到下面去
How could I go down without the golden body?
哎呀　这下可惨了　连金身都被人家拿走
What a pity!
He's even cheated me out of my golden body
大种⋯
Dai Jung…
大种
主公　我一定照你的吩咐
Lord, I'll do as you instruct me
帮你完成你的大业
and help accomplish your mission
有话好说嘛
不要这样好不好
拜托⋯先留下来　有话慢慢说嘛
Hey… don't be like that?
你们不要这样嘛
Hey… brothers…
怎么连这点面子都不给
Won't give me a face?
好歹我也是这儿当家的
I'm in charge here
早跟你说过不要这么做的嘛
I told you not to do this
怎么回事啊
What's the matter?
里面那票神仙说
As you have consorted with evil spirits,
这一次你跟邪魔打交道
the fairies inside said…
他们都不愿意跟你在一起了
…they don't want to be with you
所以呢　全都跑光了
They've all gone These just returned to get their luggage.
这一群人是回来搬行李的
对不起啊　为了我的终身俸
Sorry, for my life-long emoluments,
只好跟着大家走了　看着办吧　啊
I have to follow them… goodbye
搞什么鬼啊　东西呢
What's happening? Where's the stuff?
济癫　那个金身呢
Mad Monk, where's the golden body?
你死定了　惹这么大的祸
Oh no! You've caused big trouble
糟了　土地公也不见了
Oh no! Even God of Earth is gone.
哎呀　这次祸闯大了
We're in deep shit now
Oh no…
师傅　快走了　师傅　快走吧
师傅　你要到哪儿去
Master, where are you going?
济癫　我早跟你说过
Mad Monk, as I told you,
那个金身是不能离开寺庙
the golden body cannot leave the temple
现在弄得人神共愤
Now you've caused anger among men and gods
我怎么担得起呀
how can I bear this responsibility?
师傅⋯快走吧⋯待会儿打雷下来⋯
Master, leave quickly
师傅⋯
Thunder may split the temple
啊
阿弥陀佛⋯
- You blame me too?    - Let's go… even the Goddess is down.
连你也怪我
Go…
你还原
Back to original form
真的是逼我走绝路
You really leave me no way out?
哎　小玉
Siu Yuk, I heard you were messed up by Master Tin last night
哎　小玉　听说你昨天晚上被天爷搞坏了
Is that true?
是不是真的
去　她不理我
Ignoring us! What's so special?
叫也不理　有什么了不起嘛
You're rotten. We'll look for Siu Hung
等一等
Wait
啊　叫我啊
What's the matter, Miss Siu Yuk?
我不收你们的钱　你们肯不肯要我
If I don't charge you money, would you take me?
哎　好啊　我们马上就来
Yes, do it now
我也要⋯
Me too
Hey… She asked me first
她先叫我的　当然我先
- Me first…    - Me first…
什么时候轮得到你们两个
Who says it's your turn?
- Me first…    - Me first…
好啊　一起上也可以
你告诉我　要怎么样你才开心
Tell me, what will make you happy?
嫁给你
Marrying you
哎⋯别开玩笑
You're naughty
嫁给你啊
Marrying you
你是不是嫁给了我
If I marry you, will you stop being a whore?
就不再做〝野鸡〞了
不做
Yes
真的吗
Really?
是真的
Yes
娶了
We'll marry then
我降龙罗汉　法号济癫和尚
I am Dragon Fighter Lo Han, priest name Mad Monk
今天愿娶白小玉为妻
I'll take Bak Siu Yuk as my wife today
无论前世种种　今生何样
Whatever comes in this life or came in the past life,
此生永不言悔
I'll not regret it
但是我一双玉臂千人枕
Even I've been pillowed
半点朱唇万客尝　你也⋯
and kissed by thousands of people,
哎　不要紧　我承受得了
you still…
Never mind, I can take it
Yeah…
你真的爱我
You really love me?
我⋯我好爱你
I love you very much
你爱我有多深呢
How deep is your love?
就好像爱大种一样
As deep as I love Beggar Dai Jung
跟大种一样
Beggar Dai Jung?
哎　是啊
那你爱谁多一点
Who do you love more?
一样啊
The same
哦　我好怕
Scared me! I thought you loved him more
你爱他比爱我多一点
不⋯一样
No… the same
Yeah…
怎么你不开心啊
Yeah… why are you not happy?
我⋯耶⋯
No… Yeah…
好棒啊　拜堂吧
Great… Let's worship the ancestors
好
Good… go…
拜完堂我们就马上圆房
After that we'll consummate our marriage…
要快一点
- We must be quick…    - …then we'll have kids
立刻生孩子
我怕来不及了
I'm afraid there's not enough time
干吗来不及
Why?
如果我们神仙跟凡人结合的话
If we fairies join earthlings in marriage,
天庭就会惩罚我们
Heavens will punish me
慢慢地就会变成一块木头了
I'll gradually turn into a log
不许你说这种话
Don't say that…
啊⋯你的脚⋯
Your foot
变了
It's changing
臭小子　你在骗我的　对不对
Bloody punk, are you making fun of me?
我⋯现在不要谈这些
Hey… let's not talk about this now
快点　我们先拜堂吧
Let's carry on with the worship
我嫁给一个木头人干吗
Why should I marry a piece of wood?
你当我白痴啊
You take me for a fool?
没关系⋯
It's alright… As long as you don't back out on your promise
只要你不要反悔不嫁就行了
我嫁你妈
Marry yourself
你发过誓的
I vowed
是你发的誓
It's your vow
哎⋯我不管你嫁不嫁
I don't care if you marry me or not
反正你不可以再当妓女了
You promised you won't be a whore anymore
用不着你管
That's none of your business now
臭娘们　你耍我是不是
Bloody punk… are you playing a joke on me?
没错　我是在耍你
Yes, I am
神仙了不起吗
Do you think a fairy can get away with everything?
你对我一点感情都没有
You've no feelings for me
你以为我不知道
You thought I didn't know?
我什么都知道
I know everything
这一次我输了
A total loss this time
什么都没有了
I've nothing now. Really, nothing at all
真的什么都没有了
既然你不要我
Since you don't love me,
这一辈子我再也不要什么爱情了
I don't want love ever again in this life
不要
Don't…
我再也不要爱情
I don't want love again in this life
救命啊
Help…
杀了你就刚好凑足了
Killing you will just make enough blood
七七四十九人的血
from 77491 people
主公　我现在就拿济公的金身浸下去
Lord, I'll immerse with the golden body of Mad Monk
就算他找到了　武功也已经全废
Even if he finds here, his kung fu would be gone
你终于出现了吧　不过已经没有用了
Here at last? But it's no use anymore
就像只死狗一样
You're like a dead dog
天字派的出来
Gods appear
罗汉压顶
Lo Han on top
天将神助
Heaven Soldiers reinforce
把那个王八蛋给我抓过来
Get that bastard for me
哼　九世恶人　我看是你恶还是我恶
Villain of 9 lives, let's see which of us is tougher?
你是打不死我的
You can't kill me
嘿　是吗
Really?
呸
打死你⋯
See which of us is tougher…
我打死你　打死你⋯
I'll kill you…
哎⋯我们跟上面谈判好了
Dragon Fighter, we came to terms with Heaven
只要你肯认输　再连降三级
If you admit losing and downgrade three levels,
你就可以再做神仙呢
you can be a fairy again
现在时间不多了　快点回去吧
Time is running out, go back quickly
我把他先给解决了
Let me get rid of him first
那就快点
Hurry
王八蛋　我早该杀了你
Bastard, had I killed you
要不然也不会死这么多人
many lives would have been spared
黑罗煞的皮
The skin of Hak Lo Sat?
主公帮我换了一个千年不死的心
Lord has given me an immortal heart
哼　你们是弄不死我的
you guys can't kill me
看清楚　你的千年不死心
Look clearly at your immortal heart
石头　怎么会这样
What? A stone? How can this be?
主公
My lord…
他不但让你死心　而且还对他死心塌地的
This is a fatal heart.
He just wants your dedication to him
主公　你骗我
Lord… you fool me…
哎呀　骗你就骗你了
So what?
像你这种傻瓜　不骗你骗谁呀
You're such an ideal fool to be cheated
黑罗煞有什么阴谋　快说
What treachery has Hak Lo Sat planned? Speak.
骗我
You fool me…
说　不然我劈死你
Speak… I'll chop you.
好　我说
Don't… Ok! I'll speak
当年佛祖为了不让黑罗煞上到人间去
To stop Hak Lo Sat from going to the mortal world,
就把他的权杖放在国清寺的观音下面
Buddha placed his sceptre under the Goddess statue in Guo Ching Temple
骗你的金身
To cheat you out of your golden body such that all the fairies fled
搞到所有神仙全跑光了
这都是他的奸计
This is all part of his treachery…
目的就是要国清寺没有神力的庇护
…to rid the temple of heavenly protection
他就趁着今天晚上月蚀至阴的时候
Then at the time when the moon is in eclipse tonight,
取回他的权杖
he plans to get back the scepter
那这样要死很多人了⋯
That will cost many lives…
哎⋯阿龙啊　没有时间了
Dragon Fighter, we're running out of time
再不回到上面去
If we don't go up now,
我们三个都要留在凡间卖槟榔了
we've to stay on earth to sell bananas
快走了
Go.
好难过　把心还给我　我不想死
It hurts! Give me back my heart
I don't want to die
你不想死
You don't want to die?
大种乞丐　这里的几十条人命
Beggar Dai Jung and the others live here,
难道他们该死吗
do they want to die either?
你的那条命早就没了
You're already lifeless.
就算把这块烂石头拿回去
Even if you take back this lousy piece of stone
还是一样做黑罗煞的傀儡
you can only be the puppet of Hak Lo Sat,
继续滥杀无辜　你是不是想这么做
and continue killing innocent folk. Is that what you want?
是的话你就拿回去吧　拿
If so, get it back! Take…
下辈子不要再让我做人
Don't let me be a man in the next life then…
搞定
Fixed! Let's go
哎⋯走了⋯
Dragon Fighter, go
我们不能走
Not yet
你疯了　现在不走就没有机会了
Are you crazy?
Go now or never
黑罗煞是罪魁祸首　我要摆平他
Hak Lo Sat's the ringleader.
I must finish him off
你们先走吧
You go up first
哎⋯降龙
Dragon Fighter…
来不及了
Hey… can't wait anymore
降龙⋯
Dragon Fighter…
真的在这里
Really here
我现在给你佛法加持
I'll now endow you with spiritual powers
将我十三世的修为全放在你身上
from my thirteen life cycles’ training
今晚全靠你　你知道吗
Everything depends on you today, understand?
来吧
Come on
好
Good
Wow
哎呀　糟了
Damn
Wow
济癫
- Mad Monk…    - Master…
师傅
济癫
- Mad Monk…    - Master
师傅
我们又见面了　啊　快走吧
We meet again, let's get out of here quickly
师傅　你干吗来这里呀
Master, why are you here?
我不应该在最危急的关头
At such a critical moment, I shouldn't have left you on your own
把你一个人留在寺庙里面
你知道我处境危险　你干吗回来找我
Why care to come back for me if you know the danger?
因为我一直最欣赏的人就是你
Because you're the one person I admire most
快走
Come again! Let's go quickly
师傅　我的金身所剩无几
Master, there's not much left of my golden body
只有使出最后一招
I must use the last resort
将剩下来的金粉打入黑罗煞身体
I'll fight the remainder into his body
才能制服他
to overpower him
金身耗尽　你也会被毁灭
You'll perish too when your golden body is used up
顾不了这么多了
No time to be bothered with that
那你怎么打入他体内
How are you going to do it?
只有麻烦你把他的嘴张开
Just help me to open his mouth
这么简单
That simple?
行不行
Can you?
当然不行
Of course not
师傅⋯你怎么了
Master… Are you alright, master?
我的钵
My bowl
金粉呢　师傅　你该不会是⋯
Where's the golden powder?
Master, didn't you…
是啊　我全吞下去了
Yes, I swallowed it all
啊　在这么危急的关头　你竟然⋯
At such a critical moment, you…
我也不愿意啊
I didn't want to either.
吞了这些金粉　我肚子觉得怪怪的
My stomach feels strange now
师傅　你快点想想办法　把金粉拉出来
Master, think of a quick way
to defecate the golden powder
我长期便秘
But I'm always constipated
我想起来了
I remember now
金身还有两颗金牙在我嘴里
I've still got two golden teeth
啊　好　偷东西
You stole them?
嘘　我没牙　借用一下嘛
I have no teeth so I just borrowed them
撑不住了
I can't hang on any longer… please do my last favour
师傅　帮我最后一个忙
想办法把他嘴巴张开
- What?    - Find a way to open his mouth
我决定使尽浑身解数来收拾你
I decide to use all my magic to overpower you
我好怕哟
I feel very scared
哼　怕了吧
Scared?
那跪下磕三个响头　我就饶了你
Kneel and bow three times
and I'll spare you
Haha…
笑得好过瘾嘛
What a funny laugh
济癫
Mad Monk…
济癫⋯
阿弥陀佛　南无阿弥陀佛
Amida Buddha…
早就说了嘛⋯他一定会输的⋯
See, I said he's bound to lose
输定了⋯不会赢的⋯
- I also said he'll lose    - Lose for sure,
no argument…
输定
Lose? Why would you think that?
就像大种乞丐
本来还有二十多年的饭可以讨
Just like Beggar Dai Jung,
现在不但死了　临死还是个乞丐
he could have twenty more years to beg for his living
Now he's not only dead, he died as a beggar
他害得那个〝野鸡〞刮破了脸　好可怜呢
Also, that whore was disfigured. What a pity
还有袁霸天那件事就更惨了
The case of Yun Ba Tin is worse still
临死之前呢　还多伤了几十条人命
Tens of lives were lost before he died
你说这个⋯该怎么说呢
So… it's so… so…
How should I say it?
失败⋯失败呀⋯
What a failure
Yes, failure
何止失败
Not only a failure.
如果那天让我跟他单挑　打败了他
If you let me beat him in a duel on that day,
就不会让他弄得一团糟了
things wouldn't have been such a mess
你算了吧　整天都说单挑
Nonsense…
Stop mentioning the duel
虽然大种是冤枉死的
No doubt Beggar Dai Jung
不过在他临死之前
suffered an innocent death
起码知道自己叫朱大常了
But before he died, he knew his name was Chow Yat Cheung
那就是他重新得回他的自尊
It means he got back his pride
你们看看
- Look…    - Something to watch…
这一辈子他不用再做乞丐
- He doesn't have to be a beggar this life    - Right…
小玉的脸虽然花了
但是她再也不做〝野鸡〞
而是真正的在卖豆腐
Though Siu Yuk was defaced,
she's no longer a whore
She's really selling bean curd now
至于无恶不作的袁霸天
As for the villain Yun Ba Tin
大家都知道
他在临死前忏悔是不想再做人
We all know that when he died
现在他已经转入轮回了
he said he didn't want to be a human being anymore
He's now reincarnated
今世做猪嘛　前途一片光明啊
In this life he’s a pig, he's got a bright future
请大家想一想
Let us think did Dragon Fighter win or lose?
降龙究竟是输还是赢呢
哎⋯这⋯
Well…
不管怎么样
No matter what, Dragon Fighter Lo Han no longer exists
降龙罗汉已经不存在了
啊⋯这只是开玩笑嘛⋯
You've dropped something
Lucky I pick up for you
不过又多了一个降龙尊者
But now we have a senior Dragon Fighter
Why are you here?
不会吧⋯他都可以当尊者⋯
- He'll be a senior    - Could he be a senior?
Right
一不小心就升级了
A promotion for a few grades only
加冕仪式开始
The coronation ceremony begins
恭喜你
Congratulations
谢谢
Thank you
降龙　今天你成为降龙尊者
What's your goal being made
有什么感想
a senior Dragon Fighter today?
我想成为一位和平使者
I want to be an emissary of peace and be Heaven's envoy to spread love throughout the world
代表天宫向凡间宣扬爱心
And let them know that with love, anywhere is a paradise.
让他们明白
只要有爱　哪里都是天堂